LEVI KANE

Chicago, IL 60639

oneleggedlevi09@gmail.com www.oneleggedlevi.com (773) 558-3112 www.github.com/levickane https://www.linkedin.com/in/levi-kane-8a94a155/

Full StackDeveloper

Full Stack Web Developer and leader with greater than ten years of experience in business. Highly developed skills in working effectively with a wide range of abilities and cultures. Ability to extrapolate and solve problems resulting in high performance outcomes. Fast learner with an inquisitive, positive nature and a sense of humor while espousing career as a way of life. Earned a Bachelor's of science in Kinesiology from the University of Illinois at Chicago.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Python, CSS, Vue/Vuex/Vuetify, React, Express, Pug, Flask, VS Code, GitHub, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, JQuery, RESTful APIs, Bootstrap

Projects

<u>Chicago Boating App</u> • https://chicagoboatingapp.herokuapp.com/ (June 2021) https://github.com/markdrecoll/chicagoboatingapp

- A custom project built during the last month of the Northwestern Coding Bootcamp
- Built dynamic/responsive web page to display a 7 day Marine Weather Forecast for Chicago.
- Conditional rendering for logged-in users complete with the ability to create, read, update and delete itineraries for each day.
- Technologies: JavaScript, Express, Axios, MongoDB/Mongoose, React-Bootstrap, React, and Google-Map-React

<u>Expense Tracker 7000</u> • https://expense-tracker-7000.herokuapp.com/ (May 2021) https://github.com/levickane/expensetracker7000

- A custom project built during the 2nd month of the Northwestern Coding Bootcamp
- A dynamic/responsive web page to track finances using Heroku's JawsDB and API calls
- Technologies: JavaScript/JQuery, HTML, Bootstrap, Node, Express, Handlebars, MySql, Sequelize and Chart JS

Expense Tracker 5000 • levickane.github.io/expensetracker/

(April 2021)

https://github.com/levickane/expensetracker

- A custom project built during the first month of the Northwestern Coding Bootcamp
- A dynamic/responsive webpage to track finances using Local Storage and API calls
- Technologies: JavaScript/JQuery, HTML, CSS, Fetch API, Materialize, Local Storage

Experience

Oak Street Health, Chicago, IL

(8/2021 - Present)

Software Engineer

- Implementation of full-stack, dynamic functionalities, using the Vue framework.
- Experience working in 2 week sprints producing high quality, dynamic, scalable, testable code, using an agile methodology workflow

PechaKucha, Chicago, IL

(6/2021 - 8/2021)

Front-End Software Developer Engineer (Contract)

- Implemented new dynamic functional components based on user feedback and requests.
- Produced and displayed user analytics on custom dashboard for admin users and company stakeholders
- Developed scalable conditional rendering with CRUD functionalities and database manipulation, dependent on specified user access.
- Refactored and maintained legacy code.

New Game Plus, Chicago, IL

(11/2020 - 2/2021)

Full Stack Developer (Internship)

- Built dynamic company website using Vue/Vuex www.newgameplus.live
- Built dynamic dashboard with Vue/Vuex/Vuetify/Firebase/Firestore to display traffic analytics to, from and within the program. Data pulled from multiple API's. Displayed on chart.js.

One Legged Levi LLC, Chicago, IL

(2016-2020)

Personal Trainer/Entrepreneur

- Client abilities ranged from novice exercisers to professional athletes
- Short and long term paying clients totalling over 200
- Achieved ambitious 15 year business goals within 3 years
- Objectives accomplished by working weekdays only
- Maintained and Optimised SEO for Business Website
- Proficient in Microsoft Office

Accomplishments

Dare2Tri Paratriathlon Club, Chicago, IL

(2012-2016)

Elite Athlete

- 1st place 2015 National Championship
- 2nd Place 2015 ITU World Championship
- 3rd Place 2015 ITU Continental Championship
- First ever in the world, Single Leg Amputee, to run a sub 20 minute 5K race (2015)
- Maintained personal Website
- Regular public speaking in front of large audiences and company stakeholders

EDUCATION

Certificates:

Bootcamp Certificate: Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

 A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Computer Science applied to JavaScript, Browser Based Technologies, API Interaction, Python, Deployment and Command-Line Fundamentals, Databases, Quality Assurance, and Server Side Development encompassing the MERN Stack,

Python Development: Team Treehouse, teamtreehouse.com

 A self paced, online course built to teach new developers how to write code in Python through the Python Web Development Track. Courses covering the basics of Python and SQL as well as more advanced web applications using the Flask Framework.

Schools:

University of Illinois at Chicago: Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science in Kinesiology, December 2016